<resources>
    <string name="app_name">101ToComputerScience</string>
    <string name="title_activity_history_of_languages">HistoryOfLanguages</string>
    <string name="greetings">"
Welcome!

In this app I'll talk about Computer Science and coding - a field that has existed only quite recently
and even more recent getting well known and popular.

This is only a basic covering about the topic, but the goal is to spark interest getting to know the field more!


Before Entering the app, please fill in the info below
    "
    </string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="introduction_to_activity_learning_languages">
"In here I\'ll cover a little about basic programming concepts.

I will talk about the idea of Data Types and Variables, If Statements, and Loops.

Each topic has a dedicated button you can click on to go to.

There, you will be taught, and tested about the concept you've learned about.

Give it a go!"
    </string>
    <string name="lesson_variables_explanation">
        "So, what are Variables?"
        "Variables are used to store information, which can be about anything!\n\n"

        "Storing information serves us for many stuff, such as helping us do logic we want to do, depending on the value of the variable\n"
        "they have a name, an \"ID\" of sorts, which lets the programmer tell apart from one variable to another.\n"

        "Typically, we define variables like this:"
        "var variableName: Type = value\n\n"

        "We need to highlight to the computer that we are creating a new \'ID\', and we do that with the [var] keyword.\n\n"

        "There are different types of variables - there are those that store numbers, those that can store text, and so on. We tell the type to the computer so it can"
        "differentiate between the different types, and we\'ll write the name in place of [Type]\n\n"

        "There are many types, but we will only mention some\n"

        "[value] is where we assign the variable with the information. Note that we can change the value the variable holds later on! as we wish!\n\n\n"

        "Examples:\n"
        "var numberOfApples: int = 4\n"
        "var priceForASoda: double = 15.6\n"
        "var nameOfAuthor: String = \"Stephen King\"\n\n"

        "In the first example, we've created a variable that can hold integers, and put into it the value 4, in the second example, we created a variable that holds"
        "a decimal number and its value is 15.6, and finally, in the third example, the variable holds a sentence, and its value is \"Stephen King\"."
    </string>

    <string name="lesson_if_else_explanation">
    "Let’s talk about something very important in programming - logic!\n"
    "We can make decisions in our code by using [if] statements.\n\n"

    "[if] allows us to ask a question, and if the answer is true - we do something!\n"
    "We can also use [else] to do something different, if the answer is false.\n\n"

    "The structure looks like this:"
    "if (condition) {\n"
    "    // do something\n"
    "} else {\n"
    "    // do something else\n"
    "}\n\n"

    "The [condition] is something that results in either true or false.\n"
    "For example: [if (score > 10)] checks if the score is greater than 10.\n"

    "If that’s true, we enter the first block. If it’s false, we go to the [else] block.\n\n"

    "Example:\n"
    "if (age >= 18) {\n"
    "    println(\"You can enter\")\n"
    "} else {\n"
    "    println(\"You cannot enter\")\n"
    "}\n\n"

    "This checks if the age is at least 18. If it is, we have something that can print to the screen that the person can enter."
    </string>

    <string name="lesson_for_loop_explanation">
    "What if we want to repeat something many times?\n"
    "That’s where \'for loops\' come in!\n\n"

    "for loops allow us to run code again and again, in a structured way.\n"
    "Usually, we repeat over a range of numbers, or over items in a list.\n\n"

    "The structure is simple:"
    "for (item in something) {\n"
    "    // do something\n"
    "}\n\n"

    "We’ll often use [0 until N] to count:\n"
    "for (i in 0 until 5) {\n"
    "    println(i)\n"
    "}\n\n"

    "This loop will print the numbers 0, 1, 2, 3, and 4.\n"
    "It repeats the block 5 times — once for each number in that range.\n\n"

    "We can use this to do many things: move characters, calculate sums, or run logic multiple times!"
    </string>
    <string name="motives_for_app">"
- I didn't just choose this idea for a project - programming is something that is very close to my heart, and I see it as extremely fun (except the hundred moments when I want to tear my hair out).


Beyond school hours, I engage in a wide variety of software-related activities - I have designed and built games (via Godot, or Minecraft Plugins), I am on the robotics team in a software group studying and researching robot code, I take courses at the Open University of Israel, and generally in my free time I watch educational videos about programming on a wide variety of topics.

I would like to share this passion with the outside world, so I see this project as a good opportunity for that! (:


- I see software as a very powerful tool that serves a person along the way; beyond the fact that it is a strong and powerful career, it is also used for basic personal needs for everyday life, for example, for building personal websites, or for solving problems for questions that a computer is good at doing, but a person is not.

In my opinion, everyone should know how to program.


- Beyond the practicality of knowing how to program, software strengthens the power of thought - you learn to analyze and break down large problems into small parts, you learn to think algorithmically, you develop great creativity and learn how to be patient in situations where things do not go the way you would like them to, and to know how to adapt to unexpected situations.

There are a million and one skills that learning software provides, so it is important to me that others also want to enter the world.
    "</string>


    <string name="history_of_programming">"
Every app, game, or website runs because someone wrote instructions for the computer to follow. This is called programming or coding.\n\n
🔹 <b>The Early Days</b>\n
The first idea of programming came in the 1800s when Ada Lovelace wrote instructions for a machine that didn\'t even exist yet. Fast forward to the 1940s, real computers were invented—but to program them, people had to write long strings of 1s and 0s. It was painfully slow and easy to mess up.\n\n
🔹 <b>The First Programming Languages</b>\n\n
To make coding easier, we created languages that looked more like English:\n\n
Fortran (1957): For scientific work\n
COBOL (1959): For business use\n
Lisp (1958): For early AI\n\n
These were still hard to learn but much better than pure machine code.\n\n
🔹 <b>Coding Gets Easier</b>\n\n
From the 1970s to 1990s, coding became more powerful and user-friendly:\n\n
C (1972): Used for operating systems\n
Python (1991): Easy to read, great for beginners\n
Java and JavaScript (1995): Helped power the web\n\n
Now, you could write programs without being a computer expert.\n\n
🔹 <b>Coding Today</b>\n\n
Today, programming is everywhere—phones, games, cars, websites. New languages like Swift, Kotlin, Rust, and TypeScript help developers build faster, safer, and better apps.\n\n
And thanks to online tools and communities, anyone can learn to code—no need to be a math genius.\n\n
🔹 <b>The Future</b>\n\n
We\'re now entering the era of AI and machine learning, where computers can learn from data. Programming continues to grow—and whether you want to build apps, games, or solve real problems, you can be a part of it. "
    </string>




    <string name="description_of_job_1">
"What it is:
You build apps, websites, or software tools — like games, mobile apps, or even bank systems.

What you do:

Write code that tells the computer what to do.

Work in a team to design and improve programs.

Fix problems (called bugs) when things break."
</string>

    <string name="description_of_job_2">
"What it is:
You help companies use their data to find useful patterns or make smart decisions. Sometimes you even build AI like recommendation systems (like on YouTube or Netflix).

What you do:

Collect and organize large amounts of information.

Use math to find trends or make predictions.

Help companies understand what the data is saying."
</string>

    <string name="description_of_job_3">
"What it is:
You protect computers and data from hackers and viruses.

What you do:

Find weaknesses in systems before bad people do.

Build safer login systems, firewalls, and alerts.

Respond to cyber attacks and prevent future ones."
</string>

    <string name="description_of_job_4">
"What it is:
You make sure all the company’s technology (like servers, internet, and cloud services) runs without problems.

What you do:

Set up computers, servers, and cloud systems.

Help fix tech problems in the company.

Make sure websites and apps stay online all the time."
</string>

    <string name="description_of_job_5">
"What it is:
You work on making games, simulations, or 3D animations — either for fun or for serious use (like training pilots).

What you do:

Build game logic, player controls, and levels.

Work with designers and artists to bring ideas to life.

Make sure games run fast and look great."
</string>

</resources>